Guide to the Elmer J. Holland Papers, 1937-1968 AIS.1968.23
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Elmer J. Holland Papers
1937-1968
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Holland, Elmer J.
AIS.1968.23
116 Linear Feet (277 boxes)
The Elmer J. Holland Papers document the career of Holland, a member of the U.S. House of Representatives in 1942-1943 and 1956-1968. The collection includes a personal file of correspondence, memoranda, speeches, and statements, a legislative file of bills introduced, committee assignments, and constituent correspondence files relating to the armed services, immigration, post office, service academies, and veteran affairs. The collection also contains special files on local communities which include the correspondence, reports, and research data on those communities, as well as subject files of reference material used in researching background information.
Biography
Elmer J. Holland was born in Pittsburgh, Pa., on January 8, 1894, the son of Thomas and Margaret (Keelan) Holland. He was educated in the Pittsburgh Public Schools, Duquesne University, and the University of Montpelier, France, and a graduate of the Civil Affairs School (United States Army), University of Pittsburgh, and the American School Center in Shriverham, England. He served in World War I in the American Expeditionary Forces and graduated from Saumur Artillery School, France, as lieutenant in the Field Artillery. He also served in World War II as a major in the Allied Military Government in European Theater of Operations; past commander, Post 435, Veterans of Foreign Wars; member of the American Legion. He was married to the former Emily J. Wilson, of Pittsburgh and had two daughters, Janie and Christin.
Holland was a member of the Pennsylvania General Assembly in the House of Representatives (1934-1942) and served as the superintendent of highways and sewers in Pittsburgh, Pa., during part of this time (1940-1942). Holland was elected as a Democrat to the 77th U.S. House of Representatives to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of Joseph A. McArdle; he served from May 19, 1942, to January 3, 1943, and was not a candidate for renomination in 1942. He served as a member of the Pennsylvania State Senate (1943-1956) and then was elected to the 84th U.S. Congress to fill the vacancy caused by the death of Representative Vera Buchanan. He was reelected to the 85th and the five succeeding Congresses, serving from January 24, 1956 until his death in Annapolis, Md., on August 9, 1968. He is buried in the Arlington National Cemetery.
Previous Citation
Elmer J. Holland Papers, 1937-1968, AIS.1968.23, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
Series III, Constituent Correspondence Files, Subseries 1-8 (Boxes 115-195) regarding individuals, the Armed Services, immigration, Positions, Post Office, Service Academies, Veterans, and Social Security) have been closed for research for 75 years after the date of the creation of the record. With exception of the constituent correspondence files, which remain closed at this time, the files are open to qualified scholars and students for research and study.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Elmer J. Holland on December 31, 1968.
Arrangement
The Elmer J. Holland Papers are arranged in the following nine series:
Series I. Personal Files
Series II. Legislative Files
Series III. Constituent Files
Series IV. Special Files
Series V. Reports
Series VI: New Releases
Series VII: Card Files
Series VIII: Sample Materials
Series IX: Vera Buchanan Correspondence
Scope and Content Notes
The Elmer J. Holland Papers contains correspondence, memorabilia, documents, speeches and statements, reports, news releases, a legislative file containing committee assignments and activities, constituent correspondence files relating to the armed services, immigration, post office, service academies, and veteran affairs; also included are special files on local communities which include the correspondence, reports, and research data on those communities, as well as subject files of reference material used in researching background information.
Boxes numbered 64-114 contained copies of the Congressional Record which were indexed by Congressman Holland's staff. These print copies were deaccessioned since the publication exists in microform. The user must consult the micro text edition held in the microforms area of the Hillman Library.
Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- 20th century; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1989; Politics; Labor; Transportation; Speeches; Press releases; Correspondence; Politicians -- United States; Politicians -- Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania. General Assembly. Senate; Pennsylvania. General Assembly. House of Representatives; Holland, Elmer J.; Buchanan, Vera; United States. Congress. House
- Personal Files, 1937-1968; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Personal File contains Elmer J. Holland's correspondence during his political career between the years of 1942 and 1968. It also includes memoranda and voting records 1958-1967, speeches and statements 1937-1967, and other correspondence between 1957-1968.
  - Correspondence, 1942-1968; 1.
    The Correspondence subseries contains Elmer J. Holland's correspondence during his political career between the years of 1942 and 1968.
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, January- June 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, July- December 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, January- June 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, July- December 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters, Outgoing, January 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Letters, Outgoing, February 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Letters, Outgoing, March 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters, Outgoing, April 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters, Outgoing, May 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters, Outgoing, June 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters, Outgoing, July 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letters, Outgoing, August 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters, Outgoing, September 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters, Outgoing, October 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters, Outgoing, November 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Letters, Outgoing, December 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Letters, Outgoing, January 1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Letters, Outgoing, March 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters, Outgoing, April 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters, Outgoing, May 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters, Outgoing, June 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters, Outgoing, July 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters, Outgoing, August 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters, Outgoing, September 1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters, Outgoing, October 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letters, Outgoing, November 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 84th Congress, 2nd Session; 85th Congress 1st and 2nd Sessions, 1956-1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 86th Congress, 1st Session, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 86th Congress, 2nd Session, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 87th Congress, 1st Session, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 87th Congress, 2nd Session, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 88th Congress, 1st Session, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 88th Congress, 1st and 2nd Session, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 88th Congress, 2nd Session, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 89th Congress, 1st Session, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 89th Congress, 2nd Session, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Thank You Letters, Received, 90th Congress, 1st Session, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Thank You Letters Received From Labor People and Congressmen Pertaining to Automation and Manpower Bill (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Special, 1958-1968; 2.
    The Special Subseries contains memoranda, letters, invitations, photographs and voting records 1958-1967.
    - Donations, 1964-1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Crank Letters" (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
    - "Special Letters" (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
    - Invitations, Inaugural, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Invitations, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Invitations, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Invitations, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Office Memoranda, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Office Memoranda, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Office Memoranda, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Office Memoranda, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Office Memoranda, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Office Memoranda, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Office Memoranda, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Office Memoranda, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Office Memoranda, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Office Memoranda, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Voting Records (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Photographs (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Speeches and Statements, 1937-1967; 3.
    The Speeches and Statements Subseries contains Elmer J. Holland's speeches and statements between 1937 and 1967.
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Elmer J. Holland Speeches (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Subject, 1956-1968; 4.
    The Subject Subseries contains Elmer J. Holland's correspondence between 1957 and 1968 relating to city and county positions, contributions, and the Democratic National and State Committee.
    - Democratic National Committee, 1956, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania Democratic State Committee, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence Relating to City and County Positions, 1958, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Relating to City and County Positions, 1963-1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Relating to Contracts, 1957-1961 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence Relating to Contracts, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Contributions, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Legislative Files, II.
  The Legislative File contains legislation introduced by Elmer J. Holland 1956-1968, information regarding the committees on which he served, and his remarks in the Congressional Record.
  - Legislation Introduced, 1.
    The Legislation Introduced Subseries contains legislation and notes introduced by Elmer J. Holland 1956-1968.
    - H.R. 11200 To Amend the National Science Foundation Act of 1950, May 14, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - H.J. Res. 142 "Shut-in-Day", January 10, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - H.R. 2450- Engineering Bill, January 10, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - H.R. 2672- Private Bill for Relief of Haseep Milhem Esper, Public Law 85-455, January 10, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - H.R. 5018- Amend Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, February 19, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - H.R. 5019- Raise Minimum Wage under Fair Labor Standards Act, February 19, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - H.R. 5020- Reduce Maximum Work Week, February 19, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - H.R. 5126- Amend Servicemen's Re-adjustment Act and Leg. Reorganization Act, January 20, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - H.R.- Amend National Labor Relations Act, Introduced, February 26, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - H.R. 5355- To confer jurisdiction on Ct. of Claims to hear, etc. claims of United Foundation Corps of Union, New Jersey, February 26, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 6018- To increase exemption from $600 to $1000 on personal income tax, March 14, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 6199 - Establish Agency for Handicap, Introduced, March 20, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - H.R. 6421- To provide service-connection in certain mental disabilities for WWII veterans, March 27, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - H.R. 6751- Amend Public Assistance Provision of Social Security Act, Introduced, April 9, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - H. Res. 234- Requesting Resignation of Postmaster General Summerfield, April 15, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - H.R. 7588- Private Bill for Vincenzo Guliotta Salpierto, Introduced, May 15, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - H.R. 8498- For the Relief of Mrs. Cynthia Helene Estner, July 1, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - H.R. 9396- Private Bill for the Relief of C. J. Pobojeski, August 21, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - H.R. 9658- Postal Pay Raise, Introduced, January 8, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - H.R. 9659- To protect right of blind to self-expression through organizations of the blind, Introduced, January 8, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - H.R. 10785- Amend Agricultural Act of 1949- Storage of Surplus Foods, February 18, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - H.R. 10929- Amend Federal Coal Mine Safety Act- Committee on Ed. & Labor, February 24, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - H.R. 10930- Provide unemployment reinsurance grants to states- Committee on Ways and Means, February 24, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - H.R. 10975- Amend Title II of Social Security Act, February 25, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - H.R. 11190- To Prohibit Traffic in Obscene Articles, Judiciary Committee, March 5, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - H.R. 11528- Provide benefits to certain WWi veterans who were in active service on 11/11/1918, March 20, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - H.R. 11529- Amend DC Alcoholic Beverage Control permitting the serving of drinks to patrons standing, March 20, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - H.R. 12515- Manpower Bill, May 14, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - H.J. Res. 84- Shut-In Bill, January 7, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - H.R. 799- Repeal Sec. 14(b) of National Labor Relations Act, January 7, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - H.R. 800- "Continuing Prosperity Act of 1959", January 7, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - H.R. 801- Hawaii Statehood, January 7, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - H.R. 1017- Prohibit Fed. loans for Housing if to be Discrimination, January 7, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - H.R. 2167- Coal Mine Safety Act, January 12, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - H.R. 2544- Correction of Military Records, January 15, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - H.R. 2769- Amend Social Security Act, January 19, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - H. Res. 329- Authorize Committee On Ways & Means Study Imports, etc., July 23, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - H.R. 3310- Reduce Maximum Workweek, January 26, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 3570- Unemployment Reinsurance, January 29, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 3731- Right of Blind to Self-Expression, January 29, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - H.R. 4116- Private Bill for C. N. McLeod (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - H. J. Res. 216- Version of Star Spangled Banner, February 4, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - H.R. 4502- Increase Personal Income Tax Exemptions to $1,000, February 16, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - H.R. 4503 - Amend Servicemen's Readjustment Act, February 16, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - H.J. Res. 312- Equal Rights for Men and Women, March 17, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - H.R. 5246- Extend Temp. Unemployment Compensation, March 4, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - H.R. 6048- Amend Internal Revenue to Permit Deduction of Certain State Expenses by Members. State Legislature, March 25, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - H.R. 6862- Supplement Act of July 30, 1956 Providing Certain Cases Regular Status of Substitute in Postal Field Survey, May 4, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - H.R. 7283- Amend Social Security Act (Title II), May 20, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - H.R. 7630- Minimum Wage, June 9, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - H.R. 7635- Provide for Making Payments in Lieu of Taxes for Certain Mfg. Plants, June 9, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - H.R. 8353- Labor Bill, July 23, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - H.R. 8395- One-Year Moratorium on FHA & VA Mortgages, July 27, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - H.R. 8736- Provide for Donation of Surplus Commodities to States for Distribution, August 19, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 8834- Provide Health Benefit Program for Certain Retired Employees of Govt., August 26, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 11961- To Take Federal Courts Out of Running Labor Organizations, April 27, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - H.R. 10178- Awarding of Congressional Medal of Honor to Dr. Thomas Dooley, February 3, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - H.R. 10057- Establish Pilot Youth Conservation Corps., February 1, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - H.R. 8939- Authorize Conveyance Certain Real Property of U.S. to Carnegie, August 27, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - H.R. 9576- Place on Permanent Basis Certain Temporary Increase Basic Salaries for Postal Employees, January 13, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - H.R. 9945- To Amend Title II of SS Act- Allow $2,000 instead of $1,200 Outside Earnings, January 26, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - H.R. 10055- Postal & Federal Employees Pay Increase, February 1, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - H.R. 10056- Require Act of Congress for Withdrawal of Public Laws in Excess of 5000 Acres, February 1, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - H.R. 10133- To Prevent Use of Stop Watches or Other Measuring Devices in the Postal Service, February 2, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - H.R. 10166- Provide Payment of Pensions to WWI Veterans, February 3, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 10167- Extend Veterans Home Loan Program to Feb. 1, 1965, February 3, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 11453- To Assist State and Local Govt. in Improving Mass Transportation Service, March 29, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - H.R. 11480- Amend Library Service Act, March 30, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - H.R. 505- Authorize Interstate & Foreign Commerce Committee to Investigate FPC, April 19, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - H.R. 12212- To Provide Certain Subcontracts be Entered into Only in Accordance with Rules and Regs. of Small Bus. Adm., May 12, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Draft of Bill to Amend the Universal Military Training and Service Act (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - H.R. 94- Hospitalization For Those on SS, January 3, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - H.R. 1776- Continuing Prosperity Act, January 4, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - H. Con. Res. 46- To Create a Joint Committee on a National Fuels Study, January 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - H.R. 1940- Reduce Minimum Workweek to 32 Hours, January 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - H.R. 1941- Amend Federal Coal Mine Safety Act, January 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - H.R. 2246- Payment of Pensions to WWI Veterans, January 9, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - H.R. 2247- Depressed Areas Bill, January 9, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - H.R. 2248- Amend Social Security Act- Increased Benefits, January 9, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - H.R. 2593- Establishment of National Cemeteries in Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, January 12, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - H.R. 2711- Require Court-Martial for Discharge Other Than Honorable, January 16, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 2712- Require Boards to Give Consideration Evidence of Exemplary Civilian Conduct & Issue Certificate of Rehabilitation, January 16, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 3285- Provide Loans to Vets When Housing Credit Otherwise Not Generally Available, January 25, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - H.J. Res. 170- Designate March 20 as "Shut-In" Day, January 25, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - H.R. 3662- Mass Transportation Bill, January 31, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - H.R. 3663- Improved Educational Opportunities for Migrant Labor Children, January 31, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - H.R. 3664- Improve Working Conditions for Migratory and Other Farm Labor, January 31, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - H.R. 3881- Allow Deductions for College Education, February 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - H.R. 3882- Increase from $600 to $1000 Personal Income Tax Exemption, February 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - H.R. 3883- Unemployment Reinsurance Grants to States, February 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - H.R. 3884- G.I. Educational Benefits to Peacetime Veterans, February 6, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - H.R. 4116- Amend Sec. 9(b)(3) of the National Labor Relations Act, February 9, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - H.R. 4607- Provides that Railroad Employees May Retire at Full Annuity at Age 60 after 30 Years of Service, February 20, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - H.R. 4675- Amend Coal Safety Act (No More than 14 Employees in Certain Mines), February 21, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - H.R. 4676- To Prevent Use of Stop Watches or Other Measuring Devices in the Postal Service, February 21, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - H.R. 4703- Authorize Retraining of Persons Displaced from their Jobs by Automation, etc., February 21, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - H.R. 5003- To Repeal Section 14(b) of the National Labor Relations Act, February 28, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - H.R. 5004- Establish Youth Conservation Corps., February 28, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - H.R. 5005- Provide for Making Payments in Lieu of Taxes with Respect to Certain Plants owned by US, February 28, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - H.R. 5090- Provide 1-year Moratorium on Principal Payments under FHA Insured and VA Guaranteed Mortgages, March 1, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - H. J. Res. 296- Equal Rights for Men and Women, March 10, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - H.R. 5711- Amend NLR Act to Eliminate "or any Corporation or Association operating a hospital if not part," etc, March 20, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - H.R. 6308- To Allow Taxpayer to Deduct for Educational Expenses, April 13, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - H.R. 6409- Amend Sec. 8(b)(4) of NLR Act Situs Picketing for All Trades, April 18, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - H.R. 6582- Assist in Reduction of Unemployment thru Acceleration of Capital Expenditure Programs of State and Local Bodies, April 24, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - H.R. 6679- Loans to Veterans for Housing, April 16, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - H.R. 7373- Occupational Training, Etc., May 29, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - H.R. 7476- Relating to the Occupational Training Development and use of the Manpower Source of the Nation, June 5, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - H.R. 8375- Provide 1-Year Moratorium on Prin. Payments under FHA & VA Guaranteed Mortgages for Unemployed, July 27, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - H.R. 8376- Amend RR Unemployment Ins. to Provide Unemployment & Sickness Benefits for Employee Representatives, July 27, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 4)